Barry Commoner Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- 2019 Addition, 1936-2009 (Box 492-528)
  - Subject File, 1942-2008 (Box 514-528)
    - Pauling, Linus (Box 526)
      - Writings and statements concerning nuclear bomb tests, 1957-1960, undated (Box 526)
      - United States Senate, Internal Security Subcommittee, 1960-1961 (Box 526)
    - Photographs and portraits of Commoner, circa 1950-2004 (Box 526)
    - Russian language study, 1961, undated (Box 526)
    - Science and politics, 1938, 1952, circa 1962 (Box 526)
    - Scientist and Citizen (periodical) (Box 526)
      - 1964 (Box 526)
      - 1965-1968, (4 folders) (Box 527)
    - Scientists' Institute for Public Information (SIPI) (Box 527)
      - Energy task force, 1976 (Box 527)
      - SIPIscope (newsletter), 1976-1979 (Box 527)
      - Testimony in regard to the Atomic Energy Commission's draft environmental statement on the liquid metal fast breeder reactor program, 1974, (2 folders) (Box 527)
      - Workbooks, A-E, 1970 (Box 527)
      - Workbooks, H-W, 1970 (Box 528)
    - Seveso, Italy, consultant on dioxin accident (Box 528)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 528)
      - Notebook, 1976 (Box 528)
    - Society for Social Responsibility in Science, 1954, undated (Box 528)
    - St. Louis, Mo., 1966-1972, undated (Box 528)
    - Time magazine cover featuring Commoner, 1970 (Box 528)
    - United Nations Conference on the Human Environment, Stockholm, Sweden, 1971-1972 (Box 528)
    - United States Navy (Box 528)
      - Photograph of crew at air station Coco Solo, Canal Zone, 1944 (Box 528)
      - Tactical test reports, 1945, undated (Box 528)
    - United States Senate, War mobilization sub-committee and the establishment of the National Science Foundation, 1945, undated (Box 528)
    - Washington University, St. Louis, Mo. (Box 528)
      - Committee on Social and Scientific Problems, 1948-1949 (Box 528)
      - Correspondence, 1947-1960 (Box 528)
      - Miscellany, 1959-1962, 1981 (Box 528)
  - Oversize for 2019 Addition, 1967-1997 (Box OV 15-OV 16)
    Items from awards and honors received by Commoner and from a celebration of his eightieth birthday. Also included is a membership list for the Citizens Party, the progressive political party co-founded by Commoner.
    - Awards and honors
      - Certificates, 1967-1979, 1992 (Container 516, same heading), (2 folders) (Box OV 15-OV 16)
    - Citizens Party membership list, 1983 (Container 521, same heading) (Box OV 16)
    - Eightieth birthday, 1997 (Container 523, same heading) (Box OV 16)